Vichita Fongmala

linkedin.com/in/vfongmala/

SUMMARY

Experienced in Android application development on multiple millions download applications including code optimisation, source and version control, store publishing and working with cross-functional team. Led project resulting 70% decrease on manual steps to release application to stores.

EXPERIENCES

• WooliesX Sydney, Australia

 $Senior\ Software\ Engineer$

Jan. 2024 - Present

Email: vichita.f@gmail.com

Mobile: +61415324853

- Woolworths Application: Developed features of application. Led the team in the "Proof of delivery" and "Product substitution" feature development. Including A/B testing, unit testing, integration testing, data tracking, and release an application.
- $\circ\,$ Mentoring: Guided and helped junior developer on Android development upskilling.
- o Onboarding buddy: Guided and helped new joiner during onboarding process.
- SafetyCulture

Sydney, Australia

Jun. 2022 - Dec. 2023

• SafetyCulture Application: Developed features of application. Led the team in the "Folder on mobile" feature development. Integrated Android application with external bluetooth devices. Including A/B testing, unit testing, integration testing, data tracking, and release an application.

• Willow Inc.

Sydney, Australia (Remote)

Mar. 2021 - Mar. 2022

 $Senior\ Software\ Engineer$

Senior Software Engineer

• Willow Rail Application and Insite Application: Developed features of application. Implemented automation test from the ground up and integrated into Azure DevOps pipeline for both Android and iOS.

• Agoda

Bangkok, Thailand

Feb. 2020 - Mar. 2021

Senior Software Engineer
Mobile Software Developer

Mar. 2015 - Feb. 2020

- Release Management Tool: Developed an automation system to override human tasks related to releasing the applications to store for both Android and iOS.
- **Agoda Application**: Developed features of application. Including A/B testing, unit testing, integration testing, data tracking, and release an application.
- Onboarding buddy: Guided and helped new joiner during onboarding process.
- Other experiences (Available upon request)

Android Developer

Bangkok, Thailand

Aug. 2013 - Feb. 2015

Programming Skills

- Languages: Kotlin, Java, C#, C++, Swift
- Android Technologies: Koin, Dagger, Jetpack Compose, Coroutines, RxJava, Retrofit, JUnit, Espresso, MVVM, MVP, Play Store Publish
- Other Technologies: CI/CD (Azure DevOps, TeamCity, Buildkite, CircleCI), Firebase, Microsoft AppCenter, Git, Appium, iOS, RESTful API, GraphQL, Agile

EDUCATION

• KMUTT

Bangkok, Thailand

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science; GPA: 3.53

May. 2009 - Feb. 2013